Register of the German subject collection, 1873-2012
Hoover Institution Archives
German subject collection,
1873-2012
XX741
Hoover Institution Archives
144 manuscript boxes, 1 cubic foot box, 22 oversize boxes, 21 videotape cassettes, 6 phonotape cassettes, 2 phonotape reels, 1 phonorecord, memorabilia. (84 linear feet)
Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, election campaign literature, other printed matter, reports, memoranda, letters, depositions, and miscellany, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Germany, primarily since the German Revolution of 1918, and relating especially to the Weimar period, post-World War II West German elections and student radicalism, the end of the communist regime in East Germany in 1989, the reunification of Germany in 1990, and post-reunification elections.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. Use copies of all sound recordings in this collection are available. To view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives. An increment was added in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, election campaign literature, other printed matter, reports, memoranda, letters, depositions, and miscellany, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Germany, primarily since the German Revolution of 1918, and relating especially to the Weimar period, post-World War II West German elections and student radicalism, the end of the communist regime in East Germany in 1989, the reunification of Germany in 1990, and post-reunification elections.
Berlin Wall, Berlin, Germany, 1961-1989.; Elections--Germany (East); Elections--Germany (West); Elections--Germany.; Germany (East)--Politics and government--1989-1990.; Germany (West)--Politics and government.; Germany--Economic conditions--20th century.; Germany--History--20th century.; Germany--History--Revolution, 1918.; Germany--History--Unification, 1990.; Germany--Politics and government--1918-1933.; Germany--Politics and government--1990-; Germany--Politics and government--20th century.; Germany--Social conditions--20th century.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; Radicalism--Germany.; Student movements--Germany.; Video tapes.
- PRE-WORLD WAR I, 1873-1914 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Clippings, pamphlets, leaflets, newspaper issues, posters, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - General. Includes material relating to the Berlin war ministry, Kaiser Wilhelm II and the Royal Prussian Academy of the Sciences, 1897-1906 (Box 1)
  - Socialism. Clippings, pamphlets, leaflets, newspaper issues and posters relating to socialist movements and trade unionism in Germany and Switzerland, 1873-1900
- WORLD WAR I AND WEIMAR REPUBLIC, 1914-1933
  Leaflets, proclamations, election pamphlets, flyers, postcards, maps, typescripts, miscellaneous printed matter, newspaper issues, posters, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - General. Includes booklets, party membership book and memoranda relating to Gustav Stresemann, the Versailles Treaty, the Treaty of Brest-Litovsk, the Unabhangige Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands and the Saar region, 1919-1923 (Box 1)
  - Arische Freiheit, 1927
  - Atheism. Newspaper issues and leaflets, 1921-1929
  - Berlin. Post-revolution period. Handbills, proclamations, campaign literature, pamphlets, posters, newspaper issues, 1918-1920
    - Section 1. The coup of, 9 November 1918
    - Section 2. Radical left trend
    - Section 3. Against bolshevism and terror
    - Section 4. Formation of the voluntary associations
    - Section 4. Formation of the voluntary associations (Box 2)
    - Section 5a. Reichstag election, 1920 (Box 3)
    - Section 5b. Civil defense, emergency assistance
    - Section 6. National Assembly
    - Section 7. Communist parties
    - Section 11. Christliche Volkspartei. Headquarters
    - Section 14. Different parties and associations
    - Section 15. Peace
    - Section 16. The battle over the voting regions
    - Section 17. Extradition, prisoners of war and refugees
    - Section 18. Rebuilding of the economy (Box 4)
    - Section 19. Church, school and youth movement
    - Section 20. Anti-semitic movement
    - Section 21. The Kapp Putsch
    - Section 22. Communist movement in the Ruhr
    - Section 23. Revolution in Bavaria
  - Communism. Includes flyer announcing the assassination of Rosa Luxemburg and Karl Liebknecht, and booklet on German communism, n.d., 1919
  - National Socialism. Flyers, newspaper issues and Nazi flag (Box 5)
  - Political campaign literature. Leaflets, posters, pamphlets and other campaign material relating primarily to German elections after World War I, Includes items on Austrian and Swiss elections, 1913-1932.
  - Revolution, 1918-1919
    - General. Includes reports, leaflets, clippings and miscellaneous printed matter, 1919
    - General (Box 127)
    - Anti-Bolshevik circles
    - Anti-Jewish circles
    - Anti-Socialist groups
    - Arbeiter und Soldatenrate
    - Burgerrat
    - Church. Correspondence
    - Deutsche Demokratische Partei
    - Deutsche Volkspartei
    - Deutschnationale Volkspartei
    - Elections results, 1918-1933
    - Freikorps
    - Freie Jugend
    - Munich. Revolutionary publications
    - Noske. Orders
    - Polish border. Appeals to German recruits. Postcards
    - Post-war period. Propaganda
    - Pro-government circles. Appeals
    - Rote Soldatenbund
    - Soldiers, victims of violence
    - Sozialdemokratische Partei
    - Spartakusbund
    - Strikes
    - Unabhangige Sozialistische Partei Deutschlands
    - Workers, Appeals to
  - Stuttgart Weltkriegsbucherei. Clippings and transcripts of speeches, relating to the opening of the Stuttgart Weltkriegsbucherei, 1921 May 21 (Box 5)
  - Thalmann, Ernst. Leaflets relating to the campaign of Ernst Thalmann, 1932. See also Nazi period, - Anti-Nazi movement, 1933-1945
  - Weimar Republic. Posters, leaflets and clippings arranged numerically in folders according to the original folder number, Please consult the appendix for detailed description, ca. 1914-1933.
    - Folder numbers
      - 8
      - 9-12, 14-23, 25-27 (Box 6)
      - 28-41 (Box 7)
      - 42-53 (Box 8)
      - 54-67 (Box 9)
      - 68-79, 81-84 (Box 10)
      - 85-98 (Box 11)
      - 103-107, 110-111 (Box 12)
      - 112, 114-124 (Box 13)
      - 125-131, 133-135 (Box 14)
      - 136-142 (Box 15)
      - 143-152 (Box 16)
      - 153-164 (Box 17)
      - 165-177, 179-182 (Box 18)
      - 183-195 (Box 19)
      - 196-210, 212-216 (Box 20)
      - 217-235 (Box 21)
      - 236-246 (Box 22)
    - World War I maps
    - Miscellaneous reports and flyers relating to the war effort, the German Communist Party and materials belonging to the above 246 folders
    - Postcards of World War I and of prominent revolutionary leaders (Box 23)
    - Flyers, newspaper issues and pamphlets (Box 24)
    - Posters and flyers (Box 25-26)
    - Proclamations (Box 27)
    - Folder #24, posters and flyers (Box 28)
    - Proclamations, posters, leaflets and flyers (Box 29)
    - Proclamations (Box 30)
    - Folders no. 1-7 (Box 31)
    - Newspaper issues, pamphlets and flyers (Box 32)
    - Folders no. 99-100, 108 (Box 33)
    - Folder no. 101 and posters (Box 34)
    - Proclamations and posters (Box 35)
    - Folders no. 102 and 113 (Box 36)
    - Posters and flyers (Box 37)
    - Folder no. 109, posters and proclamations (Box 38)
    - Folders no. 13, 178, 211 (Box 39)
    - Proclamations (Box 40-42)
  - World War I (Box 43)
- THIRD REICH AND WORLD WAR II, 1933-1945 (Boxes 43-44)
  Clippings, pamphlets, leaflets, reports, correspondence, printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - General (Box 43)
    - General. Clippings, pamphlets relating to social and economic conditions, 1935-1943
  - "Ahnenpass," "Ahnen-tafel" and travel passes, 1933-1943
    - Leben im Dritten Reich. Pamphlet
  - Anti-Nazi movements
    - General.
    - Communist Anti-Nazi Propaganda. Camouflaged anti-Nazi pamphlets issued by the Kommunistische Partei Deutschlands. Includes writings by V.I. Lenin, Wilhelm Pieck, Franz Dahlem, Walter Ulbricht, Georgi Dimitroff, Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels, 1933-1939
    - Dohnanyi, Hans von (1902-1944). Reports and personnel records relating to H. von Dohnanyi and to the relationship between the Abwehr, the Sicherheitsdienst and Wilhelm Canaris, 1938-1945
    - World War II - Underground movements. Printed leaflet
  - Banks. "German banks their infiltration, expansion, controlling interest, branches, and subsidiaries in the Banking organizations of occupied, satellite, and other countries", brochure published by National Economic Bank, Poland, 1943
  - Concentration camps
    - General
    - Auschwitz
  - Danzig, Free city of. Travel passports of two Jewish residents illustrating their travels since in search of safe haven, 1937-1938
  - Economy. "Deutschlands Wirtschaftslage in Spaetherbst Fortschreitende Aufrustung". Typescript report, 1933(?)
  - Education. Holograph essays written by German students in includes essays on contemporary Nazi ideology and German history, 1943
  - Jews
  - Nazi party members. Reports, correspondence and depositions relating to duel fought near Berlin between Horst Krutschinna, Obergebietsfuhrer in the Hitlerjugend and Roland Strunk, Hauptamtsfuhrer in the Schutzstaffel (SS), 1937 (Box 44)
  - Racial purity. Pass book
  - Referendum, Printed proclamation relating to the referendum for combining the offices of President and Chancellor, 1934.
  - Trade unions. Includes reports from the London based Trade Union Center for German Workers in Great Britain, 1943-1944
  - Unconditional surrender. "Germany's Record and World Security," United Nations Information Office, Printed report
- POST-WORLD WAR II, 1945-1949 (Box 44)
  Pamphlets, leaflets, proclamations, correspondence, memoranda, transcripts, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - General. Includes judicial decisions, pamphlets, reports and leaflets relating to political, social and economic conditions and Allied administration of Germany, 1945-1949 (Box 44)
  - Berlin
    - "The Berlin Crisis: A Report on the Moscow Discussions", Printed report, 1948.
    - Cabaret, U.S. sector. Songs and libretto of first post-war poltical cabaret, 1944-1946
  - Leipzig. Proclamations and flyers relating to the administration of the city. Issued by the civilian and military government authorities, 1945
  - Nuremberg trials, 1945-1949
    - General. Includes copies of prison records of major German war criminals and holograph messages written by them during their trials
    - Defense. Correspondence, depositions and memoranda relating to the defense of several Germans, 1946-1949
    - Prosecution. Interrogation reports and transcripts of interrogations of former Nazi officials, 1945-1947
  - Refugees
    - General
    - German refugee reports. Reports written by refugees relating to the social and economic conditions in Silesia and East Prussia under Polish and Soviet occupation, 1948
- GERMAN DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC (GDR), 1949-1990 October 2
  Pamphlets, bulletins, official government publications, communist insignia, propaganda packets, newspaper issues and magazines, pictorial charts, and miscellany printed material, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Elections (Box 45)
    - General
    - (Volkskammer election), 1990 March 18
      - General
        - General
        - Ballots
        - Reports
        - Resolutions
        - Results
      - Allianz fur Deutschland
        - General
        - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands (CDU)
        - Demokratischer Aufbruch (DA)
        - Deutsche Soziale Union (DSU)
      - Bund Freier Demokraten
        - General
        - Deutsche Forumpartei (DFP)
        - Liberal Demokratische Partei (LDP) (Party's flag - see oversize box)
      - Bundnis '90 (Box 46)
        - General
        - Demokratie Jetzt
        - Initiative Frieden und Menschenrechte
        - Neues Forum
      - Demokratische Bauernpartei Deutschlands (DBD)
      - Deutsche Jugendpartei
      - Deutsche Union
      - Demokratischer Frauenbund Deutschlands (DFD)
      - Grune Partei
      - Grune Partei-Unabhangiger Frauenverband
      - Marxistische Gruppe (MG)
      - National-Demokratische Partei Deutschlands (NDPD)
      - Partei des Demokratischen Sozialismus (PDS)
      - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD)
      - Spartakist-Arbeiterpartei Deutschlands
      - Unabhangiger Frauenverband (UFV)
      - Vereinigte Linke (VL)
    - Communal elections, 1990 May 6 (Box 47)
      - General
      - Bundnis '90
        - General
        - Demokratie Jetzt
        - Neues Forum
      - Bund Freier Demokraten
      - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands (CDU)
      - Demokratische Bauernpartei Deutschlands (DBD)
      - Demokratischer Aufbruch-Deutsche Forumpartei
      - Deutsche Soziale Union (DSU)
      - Grune Partei
      - Partei des Demokratischen Sozialismus (PDS)
      - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD)
      - Unabhangige Volkspartei (UVP)
      - Unabhangiger Frauenverband (UFV)
  - Movements, organizations and petitions, 1951-1990
    - General, 1989-1990
    - Arbeitsgemeinschaft Homosexualitat, 1989-1990
    - Bund Revolutionarer Jugendlicher, 1990
    - Bund Sozialistischer Arbeiter, 1990
    - Bundnis '90
      - General, 1990
      - Demokratie Jetzt, 1989-1990
      - Initiative Frieden und Menschenrechte, 1989-1990
    - Churches, 1989
    - Deutsch-Sowjetische Freundschaft, 1990
    - Freie Deutsche Jugend (FDJ)
      - General, 1989-1990
      - Opposition to, 1951
    - Jakob-Kaiser-Stiftung, 1989-1990
    - Liga fur Volkerfreundschaft
    - Linkes Dokumentationszentrum, 1989 (Box 48)
    - Marxistische Gruppe (MG), 1989-1990
    - Meinungsumfrage, 1989
    - Neues Forum, 1989-1990 (Box 113)
    - Sexpeace, 1989-1990 (Box 48)
    - Sozialistischer Jugendverband "Rosa Luxemburg", 1990
    - Unabhangiger Frauenverband, 1990
    - Unabhangiges Institut fur Umweltfragen, 1990
  - Newspapers and periodicals, 1989-1990
    - General
      - General, 1989-1990
      - Andere Zeitung, Die (Leipzig), 1990
      - Andere Zeitung, Die (Magdeburg), 1990
      - Arbeiterkampf, 1990
      - Aufbruch, Der, 1990
      - Berlin Dienst, 1990
      - Berlin-Mitte Anzeiger, 1990
      - Berliner Allgemeine, 1990
      - Berliner Zeitung, 1989-1990
      - Blieb Gesund
      - Burgerrat, 1990
      - Chance, 1990
      - Dixie Report, 1990
      - Dresdner Morgen Post, 1990
      - Eisenacher Tagespost, 1990
      - Erfurter Tagespost, 1990
      - Eulen Spiegel, 1990
      - Expresso, 1990 (Box 49)
      - FDGB Review, 1989
      - Fur Dich, 1990
      - Humboldt Universitat, 1990
      - Junge Welt, 1990
      - Kirche, Die, 1990
      - Kontakt Youth Magazine, 1990
      - Mecklenburgische Volks-Zeitung, 1990
      - Mitteilungen, 1990
      - Mitteldeutsche Zeitung, 1990
      - Montag, Der, 1990
      - Neue Berliner Illustrierte, 1989
      - Neue Wernigeroder Zeitung, 1990
      - Neues Auer (Tage)-Blatt, 1990
      - Neues Deutschland, 1990
      - Nord-Berliner, Der, 1990
      - Nowa Doba, 1990
      - Olympia, 1990
      - Plural, 1990
      - Podium Eurer Probleme (PeP), 1990
      - Regionale, Die, 1990 (Box 50)
      - Rote Fahne, 1990
      - Sachsen Spiegel, 1990
      - Sonntag, 1990
      - Stadt-Anzeiger Dresden, 1990
      - Stadt-Anzeiger Leipzig, 1990
      - Stube, 1990
      - Tagezeitung, Die, 1990
      - Telegraph, 0, 1989-99
      - Thuringer Anzeiger, 1990
      - Tipp-Topp, 1990
      - Transparent, 1989
      - Union, Die, 1989-1990
      - Weimarer Wochenblatt, 1990
      - Wir in Leipzig, 1990
      - Wirtschaften Heute, 1990
      - Wochenpost, 1990
      - Ypsilon, 1989-1990
      - Zeitnot, n.d.
      - Zweite Hand, 1990
    - Political parties and organizations
      - Allianz fur Deutschland, Ilmenau-Kurier
      - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands, Neue Zeit, 1989-1990
      - Demokratische Bauernpartei Deutschlands, Bauern Echo, 1990 (Box 51)
      - Bund Freier Demokraten
        - Liberale Zeitung, n.d.
        - Morgan, Der, 1990
      - Bundnis '90/Grune Partei, Regenbogen, 1990
      - Demokratie Jetzt, Demokratie Jetzt, 1990
      - Deutsche Soziale Union, Deutsche Soziale Union-Kurier, 1990
      - Komitee der Antifaschistischen Widerstandskampfer der DDR, Antifa, 1990
      - Liberal Demokratische Partei, Thuringische Landeszeitung, 1989-1990
      - Marxistische Gruppe, Gegen die Kosten der Freiheit, 1990
      - Neues Forum
        - Panke, Die, 1990
        - Potsdamer-(Andere) Zeitung, Die, 1990
      - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands
        - Berliner Stadtblatt, 1990
        - Extra Blatt, 1990
        - Hochschulzeitung, Die, 1989-1990
        - Info Aktuell, 1990
        - Kontakt, 1990
        - Neue Sozialdemokrat, Der, 1990
        - Rosige Zeiten, 1990
        - SPD Dresden Aktuell, 1990
        - SPD Extra Blatt, 1990
        - Vorwarts, 1990
        - Vorwarts in Thuringen, 1990
        - Wochenblatt der SPD, Das, 1990
      - Sozialistische Einheitspartei Deutschlands/Partei des Demokratischen Sozialismus
        - Alternative, 1990
        - Leipzig Links, 1990
        - Links, 1990
        - O.T., 1990
        - Sachens die Neue, 1990
        - Schrittmacher, 1989
        - Volk, Das, 1989 (Box 52)
        - Volksstimme, 1989
      - Trotzkistische Liga Deutschland, Spartakist, 1989-1990
      - Vereinigte Linke, Die Aktion, 1990
  - Political parties, All documents of political parties listed are dated 1989-1990 unless otherwise stated, ca. 1989-1990.
    - General, 1989-1990
    - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands (CDU)
    - Christlich-Soziale Partei Deutschlands (CSPD)
    - Christlich-Soziale Union (CSU)
    - Demokratische Bauernpartei Deutschlands (DBD)
    - Demokratischer Aufbruch - sozial, okologisch (DA)
      - General
      - Arbeitnehmerverband Demokratischer Aufbruch (ADA)
      - Jugend des Demokratischen Aufbruchs
    - Deutsche Soziale Union (DSU)
    - Europaische Foderalistische Partei (EFP), n.d.
    - Freie Demokratische Partei in der DDR (FDP)
    - Grune Partei
    - Grune Partei (Box 53)
    - Liberal Demokratische Partei Deutschlands (LDPD)
    - National-Demokratische Partei Deutschlands (NDPD)
    - Nelken, die - Marxistische Partei
    - Potentialistische Volkspartei (PVP)
    - Republikaner
    - Sozialistische Einheitspartei Deutschlands/Partei des Demokratischen Sozialismus (SED/PDS)
      - General
      - Pressedienst. Presse- und Informationsdienst des Parteivorstandes
    - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD) (Box 54)
      - General
      - Party conference, 1990 February 22-25
    - Vereinigte Linke (VL)
  - Politics and government, See also FEDERAL REPUBLIC OF GERMANY-Politics and Government and UNIFIED GERMANY-Politics and Government, 1951-1990.
    - General, 1952-1990
    - Constitution (proposed), 1990 April
    - Dresden (Box 55)
      - General, 1990
      - State parliament, 1989-1990
    - Fourth International. XII World Congress, 1985
    - Honecker, Erich, 1989
    - Komunistische Partei Deutschlands, Sozialistische Partei Deutschlands, unification attempts, 1945-1949
    - Law Gazette of the German Democratic Republic, 1990
    - Leipzig, 1989
    - Maiziere, Lothar de, 1990
    - Ministry of State Security (Stasi), 1990
    - Ministry of Work and Social Welfare, 1990
    - Post office, 1990
    - Round Table
      - General, 1989-1990
      - Dresden, 1990
    - Sachsen, 1990
    - Schnur, Wolfgang, 1989
    - Sozialistische Einheitspartei Deutschlands. Political program, party and politbureau reports, 1975-1989
    - Telexes, 1990
    - Tisch, Harry, 1989
    - Unification (see also Federal Republic of Germany-Politics and Government-Unification and Unified Germany-Politics and Government-Unification)
      - General, 1951-1990
      - Currency unification (see also FEDERAL REPUBLIC OF GERMANY-Politics and government-Currency unification), 1990
      - Opposition, 1989-1990
    - Volkskammer of the German Democratic Republic, 10th Session, 1990
  - Subject file, 1949-1990
    - General, Includes clippings, 1989-1990, 1964-1990.
    - General (Box 56)
    - Berlin, 1990
    - Berlin Wall, 1989
    - Biermann, Wolf, 1989
    - Demonstrations and protests, 1989-1990
    - Dissidents, 1988
    - Dresden, 1984
    - Ecological movement. History, 1970-1990
    - Economic policies
      - General, 1980-1990
      - Currency unification. See German Democratic Republic- Politics and government
      - Economic reorganization in the Soviet Zone, 1949
      - Labor and labor unions
        - General, 1990
        - Freier Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbund (FDGB), 1987-1989
      - Unemployment, n.d.
    - Education
      - General, 1989-1990
      - Re-training following, October 1989
      - Universities, 1989-1990
      - Vocational training, n.d.
    - Ehrenbuch, n.d.
    - Foreign relations
      - Federal Republic of Germany, 1974
      - Soviet Union, 1983-1990
      - United States, 1985-1990
    - Gorbachev, Mikhail, n.d. (Box 57)
    - Hausbuch, 1978
    - History
      - General, 1952-1990
      - 1989 October
    - Immigration
      - General, Includes maps and brochures of Berlin and visas, 1989-1990
      - Auslander (foreigners in the German Democratic Republic), 1990
    - International interest groups, 1986-1990
    - Judicial system, 1953-1990
    - Knobloch, Heinz, 1990
    - Land reform, 1946
    - Libraries, 1987-1989
    - Mannheim Universitat study project on history of East Germany, 1981-1991
    - Maps, 1949, 1971, n.d.
    - Media
      - General, 1990
      - Sachsen,, 1990, 1982-1983
    - Military, n.d.
    - Peace movement
    - Personal experiences
      - General, Includes correspondence, 1988-1990.
      - 1989 October 7
      - Montag demonstrations, 1990
    - Political symbols of DDR
    - Wilhelm Pieck Museum, 1981-1982
    - Women, 1982-1990 (Box 58)
- FEDERAL REPUBLIC OF GERMANY, 1949-1990 October 2
  Election party material, newspaper issues, magazines, printed matter, typescripts, catalogs, newsletters, booklets, bulletins, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Elections (Box 58)
    - General
    - Posters, flyers, leaflets and newspaper issues relating to the general elections of 1949
      - Demokratische Volkspartei (DVP)/Freie Demokratische Partei (FDP)
      - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands (CDU)
      - Christlich-Soziale Union (CSU)
      - Kommunistische Partei Deutschlands (KPD)
      - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands(SPD)
      - Volkspartei
    - 1976. Pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, newspaper issues, pins and buttons, flags, and a song book relating to the general elections of, October 3, 1976 (Box 59)
      - General. Includes television debate between candidates, 1976 September 30
      - Aktionsgemeinschaft Vierte Partei (AVP)
      - Christlich-Demokratische Union Deutschlands (CDU)
        - General
        - Junge Union Deutschlands
      - Deutsche Kommunistische Partei (DKP)
      - Europaische Arbeiterpartei (EAP)
      - Freie Demokratische Partei (FDP)
      - Kommunistischer Bund Westdeutschland (KBW) (Box 60)